The universe is vast and awe-inspiring.
宇宙は広大で神秘的です
Earth and life on it are amazingly complex.
地球と生物の造りは驚くほど複雑です
これらはどのように始まりましたか
How did it all get here?
The Bible book of Genesis says
that there is a Creator.
聖書の創世記には
天地創造の記録があります
But the account is often misunderstood
or even dismissed as a myth.
しかしそれは間違って解釈され
作り話だと見なされています
Is what the Bible says
about the origin of the universe plausible?
宇宙の誕生に関する
聖書の記録は科学的でしょうか
Scientists estimate that the universe
is 14 billion years old.
科学者によると 宇宙の年齢は
およそ140億年です
This implies that the universe,
including earth, had a beginning.
つまり 地球を含め
宇宙には始まりがあります
The Bible agrees.
聖書にも 創世1章1節で
こう書かれています
Genesis 1:1 reads:
“In the beginning God created
the heavens and the earth.”
「初めに 神は天と地を創造した」
The account does not say
when or how the universe began.
創世記は宇宙がいつ どのように
始まったのかは述べていません
Rather, it focuses
むしろ 6つの期間にわたって地球を
創造したプロセスに注目しています
on the creative process
that took place on earth
over six periods of time,
which the Bible calls days.
聖書はそれぞれの期間を
日と呼んでいます
Were these six 24-hour days, as many believe?
これは24時間から成る
1日のことですか
No.
いいえ 聖書中の「日」に
当たるヘブライ語は
The Hebrew word used in the Bible for “day”
さまざまな時間の長さを
指すことがあります
can refer to various lengths of time.
Genesis even summarizes
創世記は創造の6日間全体のことを
the six days of creation as one day
「エホバ神が地と天を造った日」
とも呼んでいます
—“the day that Jehovah God
made earth and heaven.”
Each “day” in Genesis chapter 1
創世1章のそれぞれの「日」は
かなり長い期間だったに違いありません
must have spanned
extremely long periods of time.
The account’s perspective is also important.
筆者はどんな視点で
創造の期間を書きましたか
The writer describes the creative periods
地上にいる人が観察したという
視点に立って書きました
as they would have appeared
to an observer on the earth.
もしその場にいたら
1つの期間に始まった出来事が
Had someone been there,
he would have seen events
その後の期間にも徐々に進展していく
様子を見ることができたでしょう
that started in one period
and then progressed
into the following periods.
Light penetrated the atmosphere
光が大気圏を通過して
昼と夜が交互に現れます
to reveal alternating day and night.
Earth was covered with water,
地表は水で覆われ
大気は水蒸気で満ちています
and vapor filled the air.
The dense clouds lifted
from the waters that covered the earth,
厚い雲が地表を覆っていた
水から上昇し
forming an expansive sky between them.
広々とした空間が水と雲の間にできます
Water receded to uncover dry ground,
水が引いて乾いた地面が現れ
and the first plants appeared.
植物が芽生えます
The atmosphere cleared further
大気が透き通り
太陽と月が見えるようになります
to reveal the sun and the moon.
God created living creatures in the sea
神は海の生き物と空を飛ぶ
生き物を造ります
and flying creatures above.
And in the last period,
最後に神は陸生動物と人間を造ります
God created land animals and humans.
創世記の記録は聖書の
次の言葉と調和しています
In harmony with the Genesis account,
the Bible says:
“Of course, every house
is constructed by someone,
「言うまでもなく 家は全て
誰かによって造られるのであり
but the one
who constructed all things is God.”
全てのものを造ったのは神です」
The Bible does not speak
in scientific detail,
聖書は細かな点に触れてはいませんが
but its account of creation
is logical and reasonable.
創造に関する記録は
論理的で筋が通っています
聖書はほかのさまざまな疑問にも
The Bible also offers
logical and reasonable answers
論理的で筋が通った答えを述べています
to other important questions.
Does our planet exist for a purpose?
地球が存在しているのはなぜか
What is the meaning of life?
人は何のために生きているのか
What does the future hold?
将来はどうなるのか
To see the Bible’s answers, go to jw.org®
聖書の答えを知りたい方は
jw.org®をご覧になるか
or fill out the online request
for one of Jehovah’s Witnesses
オンラインで訪問を申し込み
to visit at a time
and place convenient for you.
ご都合の良い時間と場所を
お知らせいただくこともできます